<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jonathan Loscalzo</title><link>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content on Jonathan Loscalzo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:03:32 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Documenting Python code with Doctstring</title><link>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2021/02/documenting-python-code-with-doctstring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 14:59:26 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2021/02/documenting-python-code-with-doctstring/</guid><description>It is important for a project to have a documentation on methods, classes and modules is one step to enhance quality on it. Not to confuse &amp;ldquo;block comments&amp;rdquo; (using #) with docstring comments.
Next developers generation will be thankfully with your graceful documentation (or not, but you must write it anyway)
I&amp;rsquo;ve started using this plugin for vscode: Python Docstring Generator(njpwerner.autodocstring) with snippets for docstrings, but also Pycharm generates docstring automatically.</description></item><item><title>Don't we need DS? Summary</title><link>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2021/01/dont-we-need-ds-summary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 14:49:11 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2021/01/dont-we-need-ds-summary/</guid><description>The original article is here
I think this article will be a trigger of next datascience courses DS is attracting more and more people every day, also from a different domains. Sometimes, those people doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a PhD or a degree, and of course they could solve ML/DL problems because they are smart! (such Elon Musk :-) ). ML/DL/AI are the new buzzword, and all people want it, though they don&amp;rsquo;t know why or how&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Python: some advance topics</title><link>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2021/01/python-some-advance-topics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 18:10:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2021/01/python-some-advance-topics/</guid><description>Links Async-Await Async IO - Real Python python async features - Real Python GIL and concurrency The Python interpreter is not fully thread-safe, in order to support multithreading there is a &amp;ldquo;global lock&amp;rdquo; in CPython. Other implementations doesn&amp;rsquo;t have GIL, such Jython, IronPython. Cython has GIL but it can be released by a &amp;ldquo;with&amp;rdquo; statement.
Global Interpreter Lock - GIL Thread State and GIL multithreading vs multiprocessing multithreading in python Faster web scraping - Nick from RAPIDS Conventions: PEP 8 - Style Gide for Python Code PEP 257 - Docstring conventions PEP 518 - Specifying Minimum Build System Requirements for Python Projects (aka pyproject.</description></item><item><title>Docker Swarm - From Dev to Prod</title><link>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2020/12/docker-swarm-from-dev-to-prod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 14:50:12 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2020/12/docker-swarm-from-dev-to-prod/</guid><description>Docker Swarm tips - Links I gathered some links that helped me to enhance my knowledge to carry out docker to production.
Also, it is important to read ssh tips.
Cheatsheets docker compose bash General (docker, swarm and machine) https://docs.docker.com/compose/ docker swarm services, contraints https://docs.docker.com/registry/recipes/nginx/ docker-swarm, deploying a spring boot microservices on aws docker-swarm rocks: my excuse for using docker and swarm!</description></item><item><title>SSH some tips</title><link>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2020/11/ssh-some-tips/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 07:42:31 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2020/11/ssh-some-tips/</guid><description>SSH: Information Tips I gathered some articles that helped me and I usually take them into account.
SSH CheatSheet
Manage Multiple SSH key pairs
AWS - Connecting to your Linux instance using SSH
Find active SSH connections on linux</description></item><item><title>Diverse Topics in Machine Learning</title><link>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2020/11/diverse-topics-in-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 13:58:29 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2020/11/diverse-topics-in-machine-learning/</guid><description>Diverse Topics in ML I am going to gather diverse topics regarding to ML, but I won&amp;rsquo;t discuss none of them. I gathered them because these are not technical topics per se, are more related to theory or part of the ecosystem.
When I will able to add more, I will do.
General: Machine Learning from Wikipedia AI transform playbook machine-learning-yearning statistical inference in one sentence [data jujitsu][http://radar.</description></item><item><title>Regression Metrics</title><link>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2020/10/regression-metrics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 11:44:43 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://jonathanloscalzo.github.io/2020/10/regression-metrics/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a summary of the most common regression metrics, and when to use each one.
Metrics:
Mean Squared Error - MSE Root Mean Squared Error - RMSE Mean Absolute Error - MAE R squared - R² MSE: Mean Squared Error It is the average between the differece of prediction and real data, squared. It is a loss function, so to optimize we will try to minimize it.</description></item></channel></rss>